Ifrah Mohamed

(206) 240-3203 | Ifraham206@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ifrahm22 | ifrahmohamed.com | Seattle, WA

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Programming: JavaScript • Node.js • Java • Python • R • PHP/MySQL • SQL • HTML • CSS

Design: Interaction Design • Use Cases • Wireframes • Rapid Prototyping • User Personas

Research: Affinity Diagrams • Customer Experience and Journey Maps • Contextual Inquiry • Survey & Interviews

Tools: Figma • Marvel • Photoshop • Power BI

Courses: Computer Programming I & II • Web Development • Statistical Computing • Mobile Design • Design Methods

EDUCATION

University of Washington

Sept 2018 – June 2022

B.S in Informatics (Human-Computer Interaction), Information School, GPA: 3.5

EXPERIENCE

ServiceNow, Program Management Intern

June 2021 - Sept 2021

- Coordinated and executed project using Smartsheet while maintaining communication with Engineering Managers
- Transformed Mobile Release Calendar from manual process using excel to an interactive Smartsheet calendar
- Decreased calendar update times from 30 to 1 minute, maximizing efficiency

UCSD Design Lab, HCI Research Intern

June 2021 - Sept 2021

- Designed high-fidelity design probe of a SD tribune article using Figma]
- Designed and developed question and answer feature linked to data visualization to promote crowdsourcing
- Conducted Interviews 4 journalists and Data Science Instructors and preformed a qualitative analysis

Microsoft, Data Science Intern

June 2018 - Aug 2018

- Transformed 1000 data entries into visualizations with Power Bi to display traffic flow in intersections from live streams
- Collaborated with fellow teammates to create an innovative program featuring image video analytics that reads traffic lights in partnership with the city of Bellevue. Presented project content at two showcases at end of internship

PROJECTS

Trackity — Front-End Developer

June 2021

- Front-end developer on a job application tracker web app targeted towards undergrads
- Implemented login functionality utilizing firebase, increased interactivity, applied good practice UX writing resulting in an improved user experience

Life in Lockdown — Front-End Developer

Nov 2020

• Front-end developer on a 24hr hackathon collaboration project that gives a holistic view of the problems people face in quarantine using Unreal Engine 4.

What's That Word — Full Stack Developer

Feb 2020

• Created a website that allows the user to enter a word in a text box and choose a category utilizing the fetch API to asynchronously request and process response data on the site using JavaScript.

A Helping Hand — UX Designer/ Research

Mar 2019

- Lead UX designer in creating a high-fidelity social platform using Figma to help seniors and their caretakers with daily activities.
- Drove ideation from general platform to being more user tailored through extensive user research on seniors housing decision making

LEADERSHIP

• National Society of Black Engineers, Region VI Finance Chair

May 2020 - May 2021

• National Society of Black Engineers, Programs Chair (UW Chapter)

Sept 2019 – June 2020

• Somali Student Association, Internal Development (UW Chapter)

Sept 2019 - Jul 2020

CERTIFICATION

• Google, Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

Sept 2021